https://amazonwatch.org/privacy-policy

Our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service
Amazon Watch is committed to preserving your privacy and safeguarding your personal information
Last revised on November 30th, 2018
The following statement describes the general practices for the collection, storage, and removal of personal information on our website.
What is your relationship to Amazon.com?
Let's get this question out of the way first, since we hear it a lot. Amazon Watch is a small nonprofit organization founded in 1996 to protect the rainforest and advance the rights of Indigenous peoples in the Amazon Basin based in Oakland, California. Amazon.com, Inc. is a gigantic multinational internet retailer with a multitude of subsidiaries which is one of the most valuable public corporations in the world and among the largest employers in the United States.
Suffice to say, we have absolutely no connection to Amazon.com at all!
At times, we have called out Amazon.com for things like using fuel derived from crude oil extracted from the Amazon rainforest in their delivery fleets, but please do not contact us if you ordered a wristwatch from them online and it hasn't arrived. We swear that we know less about that than you do. And we certainly cannot help you with information that you submitted to their website or ads that you may have seen there.
What information do you collect, and what do you do with it?
Generally speaking, we only collect the information necessary to carry out the action that you, the user, are initiating (for example, signing a petition or making a donation). We do not collect other personal information surreptitiously (for example, via tracking cookies from other sites or services). As a rule, what you voluntarily submit to us is what we receive, and we use it for the purpose that you intended.
Amazon Watch sends out an email newsletter with action alerts, updates, and appeals on a regular basis. We do not automatically subscribe anyone to our mailing list, and you are free to take actions on our site or use any of its other features without subscribing to our email list. We offer the option to subscribe to our email newsletter on our action and other forms, and some folks have also subscribed in person at events or via joint actions that we may undertake with allied organizations on their websites.
If you do choose to subscribe, we won't inundate your inbox, and you can unsubscribe at any time via the links that are included in all of our emails to this list. If you have any difficulty with that process or have other questions, you can reply to the email that you received or contact us by phone or mail.
Amazon Watch does not sell or trade names or other personal data that we collect on our website.
Is my credit card information secure?
Credit card donations through our web site are processed by PayPal Pro. You may also opt to donate directly via the PayPal website, and at times we may use other clearly-identified services such as Eventbrite or Square to sell tickets for events or accept donations at them. All of these services are verified and secure payment processors, which is why we use them.
Amazon Watch never receives or stores your credit card information in any format, so there is no risk that it might be hacked or disclosed. As required by law, we keep a record of your donation and contact information (name, email, etc.) in our database of supporters, and we may follow up with you about your donation or other support later, as well as sending you tax receipts as required by US law. Please feel free to contact us at any time if you would like to change how you are contacted after making a donation or to be removed from this list.
Do you use cookies?
Our website (like nearly all websites nowadays) does make use of cookies for some basic, essential tasks. We do not, however, use them in the way that they have often raised concerns about privacy by tracking users across websites. We do not receive or store any individual personal data from cookies.
For example, we make use of a common script called Google Analytics which allows us to see how many visitors view our site, which pages they view, what countries they came from, etc. This information is presented to us in an aggregated form (we see the numbers of users visiting our site, not who they are individually), and it is stored as such within the Google Analytics service. Google also operates a service to display ads to individuals and uses cookies to identify them on whatever site is displaying these ads, but we do not use this sort of service or cookie data.
We also have a few other integrated services that are intended to make your browsing experience better which make use of cookies to do so. For example, we use a service called AddThis to display buttons on the pages of our site that allow you to share the page on social networks of your choosing, and as AddThis is a service used by many other websites, it may recognize you based on a cookie that is saved on your computer and display buttons that are optimized for you in particular (for example, if you're a frequent Twitter user, it may put that button first). We don't receive any personal information as a result of this sort of interaction; it's designed just to be a convenience for you, the user.
By using our site, you are consenting to accept our use of cookies. But unlike many other sites, ours should not break badly if you decide that you do not want to accept them, since we do our best to only use them for non-critical purposes. Most browsers enable cookies by default, but you can search for how to disable them online or see this article.
What other information do you collect?
In order to prevent fraud, make sure that our systems are working properly, etc., our web server and other systems routinely keep records of data such as incoming IP addresses, browser and system info, etc. We do not mine this data to attempt to determine personal information from it, and in general we use it only when necessary to verify that our systems are functioning as intended. If you are concerned about websites gathering such information from your visits, we encourage you to consider using VPN or other anonymizing software, since this data is routinely exchanged whenever you use the internet.
What if I want to be removed?
Amazon Watch respects your privacy. If you want to review personal information that we may have collected about you or you would like to be certain that you have been unsubscribed or removed from our lists, please feel free to contact us.
Questions?
We work hard to ensure that your experience on our site is a positive one. If you have any questions about this privacy policy or your dealings with our site, or if you have feedback or suggestions about how we might improve it, please contact us.
Thank you!
Features
Support the Moratorium on the Invasion and Destruction of Amazonian Indigenous Lands!
Join the Call to Protect Earth Defenders!
Pledge Solidarity with Brazil's Resistance!
Yes, I will donate to protect the Amazon!
"The work you do is vital, and I am happy to support it."– Charlotte R. A.
DONATE NOW
